Let's dig deeper into the kind of mindset we're talking about here.
دعونا نتعمق أكثر في الحديث عن نوع العقلية التي نتحدث عنها.
Now when you work on projects for clients,
الآن عندما تعمل على مشاريع للعملاء،
you will often be facing choices.
سيكون أمامك عادة خيارات.
For example, choice of what tools to use,
على سبيل المثال، اختيار الأدوات التي يمكن استخدامها،
choice of whether to build a solution from scratch or use an off-the-shelf solution,
واختيار ما إذا كان ينبغي عليك العمل على الحل من الصفر أو استخدام حل جاهز،
choice of which pricing framework to use.
اختيار إطار التسعير المناسب.
Now while you are making these choices,
الآن وبينما تختار بين هذه الخيارات،
if you always view at the client's heart to think about
ضع العميل وأهدافه في أولوياتك
them and see how you can maximize value for the client,
اهتم بتحقيق أكبراستفادة وقيمة للعميل
it's a great long-term strategy to evolve your freelancing carrier.
فهذا التفكير هو حقًا استراتيجية طويلة المدى تُفيد عملك الحر.
Now that might seem counter-intuitive to many
الآن قد يبدو ذلك عكس أسلوب تفكير العديد
of us who are starting out our freelancing carriers.
من الذين بدأوا في مجال العمل الحر.
We're of course here to make money through freelancing and do
هدفنا بالطبع هو كسب المال عن طريق العمل الحر وفتح
many freelancing gigs with many clients to make that money,
مجالات اقتصادية للعمل الحر مع العديد من العملاء لكسب
which is our priority.
التي هي أولويتنا.
No doubt that is our priority.
لا شك أن هذه هي أولويتنا.
But when working with a mindset of maximizing value for the client,
ولكن عند العمل بعقلية تعظيم القيمة للعميل،
you will realize that will pay you back in
ستعرف أنك ستجني أرباح ذلك
the long-term as well as the short-term in numerous cases.
على المدى البعيد وعلى المدى القريب أيضًا في العديد من المواقف.
But I would say do not take my word for it.
ولكن أدعوك لتجرب الأمر بنفسك ولا تعتمد فقط على كلامي هذا.
Try it out, test,
حاول وجرب
and see where this attitude and mindset takes you.
وأنظر إلى النتائج التي تجنيها من طريقة التفكير هذه.
If a client realizes that you made them save money by working smartly,
إذا أدرك العميل أنك جعلته يوفر المال عن طريق العمل بذكاء،
like using the right tools, being efficient,
مثل استخدام الأدوات المناسبة والفعالة،
they may leave you a good review,
قد يكتب عنك مراجعة جيدة،
which would be helpful to get hired for future jobs and get more clients.
وستفيدك المراجعة الجيدة في الحصول على وظائف أكثر في المستقبل والعمل مع العديد من العملاء.
Also, if a client finds out through
وإذا اكتشف العميل من خلال
another freelancer of a more efficient way to do things,
موظف حر آخر طريقة أكثر فاعلية لإتمام المهمة
they may no longer be interested in you and may just go with the other freelancer.
فلن يهتم بالعمل معك وسيتركك ليعمل مع موظف آخر.
However, when they know that you are conscious about efficiency of time and their money,
ولكن عندما يعرف العميل أنك مُدرك لأهمية وقته وأمواله،
you might be their first choice if and when they have more work in the future.
فقد تكون خياره الأول عندما يكون لديه المزيد من العمل في المستقبل.
Lastly, it will give you the satisfaction of a job well done.
وأخيرًا، سيمنحك ذلك الرضا عن العمل الذي أنجزته بشكل جيد.